Guide to the Jane Roberts Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Jane Roberts papers
1915-2017
MS 1090
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
164.08
(498 boxes)
Jane Roberts was an author of fiction, and of non-fiction works dealing with Seth and her role as a channeler. The papers consist of correspondence, printed material, audio and videotapes, journals, poetry, and other material documenting her personal life and literary career. Many of the documents are photocopies of originals.
Roberts, Jane, 1929-1984
Seth
Conditions Governing Access
Researchers wishing to use the fan mail in Accessions 1985-M-014, 2002-M-027, and 2003-M-029 must sign an "Access agreement for the fan mail in the Jane Roberts Papers" in order to be given access to this material.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Received from Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1985-1996, 2001-2003, and 2006. Gift of Tam Mossman, 1991, 1996-1997, 2001, and 2011. Received from Richard Kendall, 1991-1992, 1995, 1997, and 1999-2001; Seth Network International, 1993-1995 and 1997-1998; Norman Friedman, 1993; Madelon Rose Logue, 1996-2017; Ron Heckens, 1999; Anita Newell and Nancy Walker, 2000; Mary Rouen/Brass Ring Bookstore, 2000-2001 and 2006; Moment Point Press, 2001; Rick Stack, 2001-2002; Jobi Harris, 2001; Barry Noonan, 2001 and 2004; Mary Dillman, 2000-2001; Sue Watkins, 2000-2001; Joyce Combs, 2002; Mike Flynn, 2002; Lucy Gillis, 2002-2003; and Sabine Lucas, 2006. Gift of Jeff King, 2011.
Arrangement
The original donations to this collection were arranged in February 1988 into the following groupings: Jane Roberts material (boxes 1-32), Robert Butts, Jr. material (box 33), Tam Mossman material (boxes 34-35), and publications (boxes 36-38). Within those groupings arrangement is basically by type of material. This 1988 arrangement is followed by numerous subsequent additions.
Scope and Contents
Jane Roberts was an author of fiction, and of non-fiction works dealing with Seth and her role as a channeler. The papers consist of correspondence, printed material, audio and videotapes, journals, poetry, and other material documenting her personal life and literary career. Many of the documents are photocopies of originals.
Biographical / Historical
Jane Roberts was born on May 8, 1929. She grew up in Saratoga Springs, New York, where she attended Skidmore College. In addition to writing poetry, short stories, children's literature, and novels, she is the author of non-fiction works dealing with Seth and her role as a channeler. Roberts died on September 5, 1984.
Reincarnation; Spirit writings; Spiritualism; Authors; Butts, Robert F.; Roberts, Jane, 1929-1984
- Inventory, 1967-1986
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Materials in this boxes 1-33 were received from Robert F. Butts. Materials in boxes 34-35 were the gift of Tam Mossman. Issues of publications in boxes 36-38 were received from Mary Dillman and others.
  - Jane Roberts' journal, 1965-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
  - Jane Roberts' journal, 1974-1977 June (Box 2, Folder 7-13)
  - Jane Roberts' journal, 1977 July-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14-19)
  - ESP class account book (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - ESP class sessions, 1967 September-1972 December (Box 4, Folder 21-25)
  - ESP class sessions, 1973 January-1974 May (Box 5, Folder 26-28)
  - ESP class sessions, 1974 June-1979 (Box 6, Folder 29-30)
  - ESP session tapes
    Scope and Contents
    These audiocassette tapes are possibly related to and duplicated by reel-to-reel tapes, audiocassette tapes, and compact discs of recordings of Jane Roberts' ESP class sessions in Accessions 1998-M-079, 2001-M-058, 2002-M-015, and 2004-M-087.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - 1970 January 30, 1 (Box 7A)
    - 1970 November 3, 1 (Box 7B)
    - 1970 December 1, 1 (Box 7C)
    - 1971 January 12, 1 (Box 7-D)
    - 1971 January 19, 1 (Box 7E)
    - 1971 August 31, 1 (Box 7-F)
    - 1971 August 31, 1 (Box 7G)
    - 1972 March 21, May 2, 1 (Box 7H)
    - 1972 March 7, April 4, 1 (Box 7I)
    - 1972 March 28, April 11, 1 (Box 7J)
    - 1972 April 18, May 30, 1 (Box 7K)
    - 1972 April 24, May 9, November 9, 1 (Box 7L)
    - 1972 May 15, 1 (Box 7M)
    - 1972 May 23, 1 (Box 7N)
    - 1972 June 13, August 22, 1 (Box 7O)
    - 1972 August 28, 1 (Box 7P)
    - 1972 August 29, 1 (Box 7Q)
    - 1972 April 11, June 6, September 5, 1 (Box 8A)
    - 1972 September 19, 1 (Box 8B)
    - 1972 September 26, 1 (Box 8C)
    - 1972 October 3, 17, 1 (Box 8-D)
    - 1972 October 31, November 7, 14, 1 (Box 8E)
    - 1972 November 27, December 5, 1 (Box 8-F)
    - 1972 December 12, 1 (Box 8G)
    - 1972 December 19, 1 (Box 8H)
    - 1972 December 19, 1973 January 9, 1 (Box 8I)
    - 1973 January 16, 1 (Box 8J)
    - 1973 January 23, 1 (Box 8K)
    - 1973 February 6, 1 (Box 8L)
    - 1973 February 6, 13, 1 (Box 8M)
    - 1973 February 26, March 6, 1 (Box 8N)
    - 1973 March 13, 23, 1 (Box 8O)
    - 1973 March 20, 1 (Box 8P)
    - 1973 December 4, January 24, February 5, 1 (Box 8Q)
    - 1973 March 20, April 3, 1 (Box 9A)
    - 1973 April 17, 1 (Box 9B)
    - 1973 April 24, 1 (Box 9C)
    - 1973 May 15, 1 (Box 9-D)
    - 1973 May 22, 1 (Box 9E)
    - 1973 June 19, 1 (Box 9-F)
    - 1973 June 26, 1 (Box 9G)
    - 1973 July 10, 1 (Box 9H)
    - 1973 July 31, 1 (Box 9I)
    - 1973 July 31, 1 (Box 9J)
    - 1973 August 14, 1 (Box 9K)
    - 1973 August 21, 1 (Box 9L)
    - 1973 September 11, 1 (Box 9M)
    - 1973 September 25, 1 (Box 9N)
    - 1973 November 6, 1 (Box 9O)
    - 1973 December 4, January 30, 1 (Box 9P)
    - 1973 December 11, 1974 January 3, 10, 15, 1 (Box 9Q)
    - 1974 January 3, 1 (Box 10A)
    - 1974 January 8, 1 (Box 10B)
    - , Part 1, 1974 January 22; 1 (Box 10C)
    - , Part 2, 1974 January 22; 1 (Box 10-D)
    - 1974 February 12, 1 (Box 10E)
    - 1974 February 27, 1 (Box 10-F)
    - 1974 February 27, March 5, 1 (Box 10G)
    - (Sumani Set), 1974 March 12, 19; 1 (Box 10H)
    - 1974 March 12, 19, 1 (Box 10I)
    - 1974 March 12, 19, 1 (Box 10J)
    - 1974 March 26, April 2, 1 (Box 10K)
    - 1974 March 26, April 9, 1 (Box 10L)
    - 1974 April 23, May 7, 15, 1 (Box 10M)
    - 1974 May 21, 1 (Box 10N)
    - 1974 May 28, 1 (Box 10O)
    - 1974 June 4, 1 (Box 10P)
    - 1973 October 2, 9, 1 (Box 11A)
    - 1974 June 11, 1 (Box 11B)
    - 1974 June 18, 1 (Box 11C)
    - 1974 June 18, July 9, 1 (Box 11-D)
    - 1974 July 2, 1 (Box 11E)
    - 1974 July 16, 1 (Box 11-F)
    - 1975 April 16, 1 (Box 11G)
    - 1975 July 12, 1 (Box 11H)
    - 1975 July 12, August 16, 1 (Box 11I)
    - 1977 April 8, 1 (Box 11J)
    - 1978 October 24, 1 (Box 11K)
    - 1978 December 2, 1 (Box 11L)
    - 1979 September 29, 1 (Box 11M)
    - Seth, Oct 16, 23, Circa 1973; 1 (Box 11N)
    - Nature of P.R., Undated; 1 (Box 11O)
    - Chapter 5 continued, Undated; 1 (Box 11P)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 1-59 (Box 12, Folder 31-36)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 60-135 (Box 13, Folder 37-43)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 136-209 (Box 14, Folder 43-49)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 210-270 (Box 15, Folder 50-56)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 271-349 (Box 16, Folder 57-63)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 350-457 (Box 17, Folder 64-70)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 458-564 (Box 18, Folder 71-77)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 565-645 (Box 19, Folder 78-84)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 646-704 (Box 20, Folder 85-91)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 705-744 (Box 21, Folder 92-98)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 745-828 (Box 22, Folder 99-104)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 829-908 (Box 23, Folder 105-111)
  - The Seth Material, sessions 909-941 (Box 24, Folder 112-114)
  - The Seth Material-notes and index for sessions 1-629 (Box 24, Folder 115)
  - The Seth Material-list of the contents (Box 24, Folder 116)
  - The Seth Material, deleted sessions D1-D3 (Box 24, Folder 117-119)
  - The Seth Material, deleted sessions D4-D11 (Box 25, Folder 120-127)
  - The Seth Material, deleted sessions D12-D18 (Box 26, Folder 128-134)
  - The Seth Material, deleted sessions D19-D26 (Box 27, Folder 135-142)
  - The Seth Material, deleted sessions D27-D35 (Box 28, Folder 143-151)
  - The Seth Material, deleted sessions D36-D46 (Box 29, Folder 152-162)
  - Writings (Box 30)
    - List of books to 1977, Circa 1977 (Box 30)
    - The Afterdeath Journal of An American Philosopher (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous Writings for Aspects Volumes 1-3 (Box 30)
    - Unfinished Bali Manuscript, 1971-1977 (Box 30)
    - Education of the Oversoul (Box 30)
    - God of Jane (Box 30)
    - The Little Artificial Christmas Tree (Box 30)
      General
      See also: Accession 2012-M-029.
    - The Magical Approach-A Jane Seth Book (Box 30)
    - Mass Events-index (Box 30)
    - Nature of Personal Reality-index (Box 30)
    - The Nature of the Psyche: A Seth Book (copyright registration card), Undated (Box 30)
    - The Physical Universe as Idea Construction (Box 30)
    - Poetry and Sketches (Box 30)
    - Seth Speaks (Box 30)
    - The Sinful Self (Box 30)
    - Sketchbooks and poetry sketchbooks (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous Sumari (Box 30)
    - Unknown Reality -index (Box 30)
    - The Unknown Reality, Volume 2 (Box 30)
    - Book dust jackets, Undated (Box 30)
  - Notebooks and Notepads (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous notes and articles, 1967-1982 (Box 31)
    - Notebooks and pads, 1975-1979 (Box 31)
    - Notebooks, 1977 January-October (Box 31)
    - Notebooks, 1978-1980 (Box 31)
    - Notebooks and pads, 1977-1982 (Box 31)
    - Notepads, 1979, 1982 (Box 31)
    - Spontaneous Events Notebook, 1964-1966 (Box 31)
    - Self and Book Chronologies to 1970 (Box 31)
      - Notes 1970-1971 (Box 31)
    - Dream Journal, 1977-1978 (Box 31)
    - Psychic Library Exercises and Notes, 1975-1978 (Box 31)
    - JRB and RFB Pendulum Questions and Answers, 1974, 1976-1978, 1981-1982, 1984-1985 (Box 31)
    - Dreams and Out-of-Body Experiences (Box 31)
  - Personal Papers (Box 32)
    - Daily Records of Jane's Hospital Stay, 1982 November-1984 July (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous medical notes for J. Roberts, 1982 (Box 32)
    - Practice Writing, 1982 (Box 32)
    - Family Histories of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr. (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Family correspondence, 1968-1980, 1999 (Box 32)
    - German language Seth news magazines, programs and correspondence (Box 32)
    - Articles on the life and word of Jane Roberts as printed in the Elmira (NY) Star-Gazette (Box 32)
    - Christmas books and cards (Box 32)
    - Cards-Rob's Book of Plants (Box 32)
    - Birthday books and cards to Rob (Box 32)
    - Frontiers of Science, 1982 May-June (Box 32)
  - Robert F. Butts, Jr. (Box 33)
    - Dream Journal, 1974 June 20-1979 July 25 (Box 33)
    - Dream Journal, 1979 August 1-1980 December 27 (Box 33)
    - Dream Journal, 1981 January 30-1983 May 13 (Box 33)
    - Dream Journal, 1985 May 25-1987 February 3 (Box 33)
    - Original artworks, undated (Box 33)
    - "The Seth Video" [visual record of Seth speaking through Jane Roberts and filmed interview of Jane and Robert F. Butts, Jr.], Kendall Enterprises, 1986
      - "The Seth Video", 1986; 1 (Box 33A)
        Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
      - "The Seth Video" transcript (Box 33)
  - Tam Mossman
    - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, Robert F. Butts, Jr. to Tam Mossman, 1982 July-September (Box 34)
    - Correspondence to Tam Mossman and unidentified, 1977-1979, undated (Box 34)
    - ALS and Christmas card to Tam Mossman from Roger at "Coordinate Point,", 1980 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 34)
    - Class Sessions, 1972-1976 (Box 35)
  - Coordinate Point
    Published by Sandra and Roger Peterson, San Francisco, CA.
    - vol I: 1-3, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - vol. II: 1-12, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - vol. III: 1-9, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      No June, August, or December issues published.
    - vol. IV :1-2, 1981 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      No February issue; March 1981 was last issue published by the Petersons.
  - Coordinate Point International
    Published by Ann and Jim Cook & Dream Team, Ciarcona, FL.
    - vol. I: 1-11, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      No February issue published.
    - vol. II: 1-12, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 6-7)
    - vol. III: 1, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      No January, February, or March issues published; April 1984 was last issue published by the Cooks.
  - Coordinate Point
    Published by Jan and Tom Sweeney in conjunction with the Orlando Seth Group.
    - vol. I: 1-4, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      No. 4 was for 1985 December-1986 January.
    - vol. II: 1-5, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      Bimonthly issues; no December issue published.
    - vol. III: 1-6, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      Bimonthly issues; 1987 November/December was last issue published.
  - Metapsychology: the Journal of Discarnate Intelligence
    - vol. I: nos. 1-4, 1985-1986 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - vol. II: nos. 1-4, 1986-1987 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - vol. III: nos. 1-4, 1987-1988 (Box 38, Folder 14)
- Additional material, 1965-1985; Accession 1985-M-014
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 1985 and 2002.
  Researchers wishing to use the fan mail in Accession 1985-M-014 must sign an "Access agreement for the fan mail in the Jane Roberts Papers" in order to be given access to this material.
  Includes accessions 2003-M-009, 2003-M-011, and 2003-M-020. Comprises Jane Roberts fan mail listed chronologically. Accompanying audiotapes and oversize materials are listed after the fan mail, also in chronological order. Fan mail is also contained in Accessions 2002-M-027 and 2003-M-029.
  - Fan mail
    Researchers wishing to use the fan mail must sign an "Access agreement for the fan mail in the Jane Roberts Papers" in order to be given access to this material.
    - 1965-1973 April (Box 1)
    - 1973 May-1974 December (Box 2)
    - 1975 January-April (Box 3)
    - 1975 May-August 11 (Box 4)
    - 1975 August 12-November 12 (Box 5)
    - 1975 November 13-1976 February 10 (Box 6)
    - 1976 February 11-May 14 (Box 7)
    - 1976 May 15-August 14 (Box 8)
    - 1976 August 15-November 17 (Box 9)
    - 1976 November 18-1977 January 16 (Box 10)
    - 1977 January 17-April 5 (Box 11)
    - 1977 April 6-July 14 (Box 12)
    - 1977 July 15-October 9 (Box 13)
    - 1977 October 10-1978 January 10 (Box 14)
    - 1978 January 11-March 28 (Box 15)
    - 1978 March 29-May (Box 16)
    - 1978 June-September 8 (Box 17)
    - 1978 September 9-December 5 (Box 18)
    - 1978 December 6-1979 February 24 (Box 19)
    - 1979 February 25-May 9 (Box 20)
    - 1979 May 10-July 31 (Box 21)
    - 1979 August 1-October 31 (Box 22)
    - 1979 November 1-December 31 (Box 23)
    - 1980 January 1-March 20 (Box 24)
    - 1980 March 21-June 20 (Box 25)
    - 1980 June 21-September 25 (Box 26)
    - 1980 September 26-December 12 (Box 27)
    - 1980 December 13-1981 February 15 (Box 28)
    - 1981 February 16-May 25 (Box 29)
    - 1981 May 26-August 15 (Box 30)
    - 1981 August 16-October 25 (Box 31)
    - 1981 October 26-December 20 (Box 32)
    - 1981 December 21-1982 March 5 (Box 33)
    - 1982 March 6-June 12 (Box 34)
    - 1982 June 13-September 30 (Box 35)
    - 1982 October 1-December 21 (Box 36)
    - 1982 December 22-1983 February (Box 37)
    - 1983 March 1-May 5 (Box 38)
    - 1983 May 6-August 8 (Box 39)
    - 1983 August 9-November 30 (Box 40)
    - 1983 December 1-1984 January 31 (Box 41)
    - 1984 January-April 20 (Box 42)
    - 1984 April 21-July 31 (Box 43)
    - 1984 August 1-November 23 (Box 44)
    - 1984 November 24-1985 March (Box 45)
  - Printed materials
    - 1975-1980 (Box 46)
    - 1981-1984 (Box 47)
  - Audiotapes
    Include accompanying correspondence.
    - 1975-1979 (Box 48)
    - 1979-1982 (Box 49)
    - 1982-1984 (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1984 (Box 51)
    Comprises Frederick Fell book catalog, newspaper articles, notes, sketches, business cards, and dream notes.
  - Oversize
    - 1975-1984 (Box 52)
    - 1975-1984 (Box 53)
  - Envelopes, 1969-1982 (Box 54)
    Envelopes do not contain letters, and were kept at request of donor.
- Additional material, 1955-1988; Accession 1988-M-066
  Includes Accession 1989-M-005 (in Box 3).
  Received from Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1988.
  - First, second, and third address books of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1955-1970s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Contains notes added by Robert Butts, Jr.
  - Excerpts from six cookbooks of Jane Roberts, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Grief notebooks #1-#3 by Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Dream Journal #6 by Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1987 February 12-1988 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous notes and essays by R. F. Butts, Jr., 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Written for the epilogue to Dreams, "Evolution," and Value Fulfillment by Jane Roberts, and includes poetry and Seth material written by her.
  - Medical notes and correspondence, 1982 April 20-1984 August 22 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Records of hours and payments of Upjohn Healthcare Services for Jane Roberts, 1982 March 10-1982 November 12 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Records of home health care of Jane Roberts by Upjohn Health Services, volumes 1-2, 1983 January 22-1983 April 4 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - "Working Chronologies", undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    This workbook was compiled by Robert F. Butts, Jr. to aid him in his production of hte manuscripts for the two volumes of Dreams, "Evolution," and Value Fulfillment by Jane Roberts.
- Additional material, 1964-1980; Accession 1989-M-014
  - Notebooks and pads of Jane Roberts, volumes 11-12, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Material for poem "I am alive again" by Jane Roberts, 1980 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Little Book to Leonard, written by Jane Roberts for Leonard Yaudes, 1980 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dream Notebooks #1-#4 by Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1964 September- 1970 August (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
- Additional material, 1965-1971; Accession 1989-M-043
  - Prediction notebooks #1-#4 of Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1965 February 1-1971 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
- Additional material, 1964-1969; Accession 1989-M-050
  Received from Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1989.
  - Prediction notebooks #1-#7 of Jane Roberts, 1964 November 5-1969 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 1-8)
  - Psy-time and ESP results of Jane Roberts, 1968 May 22-1969 January 9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Additional material, 1956-1977; Accession 1989-M-068
  - Miscellaneous notes of Jane Roberts, 1963 December-1977 June 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes Frank Watts (Withers) material, pendulum material, essays, dreams, and two short notebooks.
  - Daily Records Notebooks #1-#5 of Jane Roberts, 1956 November 12-1969 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
- Additional material, 1947-1979; Accession 1989-M-078
  - Notes on professional and personal matters by Jane Roberts, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Prediction notebook #8 of Jane Roberts, 1970 October 16-1971 February 25, 1972 December 31 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pendulum notes of Jane Roberts, 1967 January 23-1967 June 11, 1967 November-December (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Psy-time and ESP notebook of Jane Roberts, 1964 October 8-1966 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Records of short story, novel, and poetry submissions of Jane Roberts, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ESP Account Book #1 of Jane Roberts, 1967 July 18-1970 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous professional and personal materials of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1947-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Psychological time experiences of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1964 April 8-1965 March 29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Pendulum work of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1965 April 25-1974 September 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Additional material, 1947-1984; Accession 1990-M-010
  - Miscellaneous materials of Jane Roberts, Robert F. Butts, Jr., and others, 1947-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Photographs of Jane Roberts with the Butts, Jr. family and friends, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Greeting cards designed by Jane Roberts, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notes of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr. to each other, 1967 June - 1972 November (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional material, 1915-1989; Accession 1990-M-057
  Includes Accession 1990-M-058.
  Received from Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1990.
  - Greeting cards,"Off the Wall Collection," sent to Jane Roberts at St. Joseph's Hospital, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Valentine, Easter, and birthday cards (v. 1) exchanged mainly between Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1970 Junee 20 - 1984 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Christmas and anniversary cards (v. 2) exchanged between Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1961 December - 1983 December (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Account book of the work of Robert F. Butts, Jr. as a self-employed comic book artist, 1948 February 10 - 1956 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs (photocopies) of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr. and various members of their families, 1915-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
- Additional material, 1917, 1942-1990; Accession 1991-M-016
  - Selection of materials having to do with earlier events in the lives of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr. (vol. 1), 1917-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Notes by Jane Roberts pertaining to her dream projections, levitations, out-of-body travels, and other topics, 1964 April 30- 1968 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Some pages of these notes are missing.
  - Dream notebooks of Jane Roberts, volumes 1-4, 1963 October 2-1967 August 17 (Box 1, Folder 4-8)
    - Psychological time and projection experiences accompanying volume 4, Circa 1966 July 26- 1966 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Dream notebooks of Jane Roberts, volumes 5-6, 1967 August 18- 1969 January 9 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Dream notebooks of Jane Roberts, volumes 7-9, 1967-1973 July 1 (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
  - Predictions, 1972 August 18- 1972 October 5 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dream notebook of Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1988 June 1- 1990 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Additional material, 1988; Accession 1991-M-056
  Received from Richard Kendall, 1990.
  - "Jane Roberts: The San Francisco Interview," two audiocassettes and paperback, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1968-1988; Accession 1991-M-091
  Received from Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1991.
  - Business, editorial, and production correspondence pertaining to the publication of the Seth material and other books and poetry by Jane Roberts, and notes and essays by Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1968 April 3-1980 December 23 (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
    - Additional material, 1981 January 5-1988 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 14-24)
- Additional material, 1975-1981; Accession 1991-M-094